here are two standard infinite series
that are related sure you can find the
sum of these series using classical
techniques but let's see a geometric way
that computes the sum of both of these
infinite series using regular polygons
start with an equilateral triangle the
interior angle of this triangle is pi
over 3 which can be Rewritten as 2 piun
3 * 2 now draw a square around that
equilateral triangle with side length
equal to the base the interior angle of
the square is 2 Pi / 4 and so the angle
between the square in the triangle is 2
piun 4 - < 3 which simplifies to 2 piun
/ 4 * 3 Let's extend this again by
drawing a pentagon with side length
equal to the square length again the
interior angle of the Pentagon is 3 pi
over 5 so the difference in angle
between the Pentagon and the square is 3
piun / 5 - 2 piun 4 and this simplifies
to 2 piun / 5 * 4 we can continue this
extension process by drawing larger and
larger polygons around so we start with
the hexagon and then we move to the
heptagon and so on using the interior
angle theorem we see that the angle
difference between the N gon and the
nus1 gone is n - 2 * piun / n minus the
quantity n- 3 * piun / nus1 and this
simplifies to 2 piun / n * nus1 so the
angle between the regular n gon and the
regular n -1 gone is always 2 piun / n *
nus1 as we extend this picture out but
now we can just keep extending this
picture drawing more and more regular
polygons where the number of sides
increases indefinitely in fact we can
consider a limiting shape of this
process the limiting outer shell of the
resulting shape is a circle by zooming
back into the original equilateral
triangle we get an amazing fact the
angles that we've determined can be
added together so we see that on one
hand the full angle measurement is 2
piun 3 * 2 + 2un 4 * 3 + 2 piun over 5 *
4 and so on each time adding up angles
of the form 2 pi/ n * nus1 on the other
hand all of these angles together form
the full angle measurement of a
horizontal line since this line is
tangent to the circle and therefore the
sum of the angles must equal Pi but now
we can cancel the pi and the numerators
of the fractions on the left with the pi
on the right and we see that 2 3 * 2 + 2
4 * 3 + 2 5 * 4 and so on must equal 1
if we then add 2 over 2 * 1 on the left
and 2 over 2 * 1 on the right which is
one then we get our first famous
infinite sum notice that each fraction
on the left is 1/ n choose 2 where n
choose 2 is a binomial coefficient or a
triangular number this means that the
infinite sum where n ranges from 2 to
Infinity of 1/ n choose 2 is equal to 2
we can also divide both sides of the
equation by two producing another famous
infinite sum the one where n ranges from
1 to Infinity of 1 n * n + 1 and this
sum equals 1 these infinite sums are
usually computed by recognizing the
infinite series as a telescoping series
but here we've shown how to find this
infinite sum using a limiting process on
an amazing diagram constructed by larger
and larger regular polygons if you like
this video check out my playlist on
infinite series there I've animated
classic visual proofs that Compu the sum
of infinite Series in interesting ways